<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Articles (en)</title>
<link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/rss.xml</link>
<description>Latest articles (en)</description>
<item>
  <title>GitHub as an Intellectual Mine</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article posits that GitHub, beyond its role in collaborative software development, is evolving into a platform for open knowledge sharing, functioning as an "intellectual mine." Generative AI tools like Cognition's Devin and DeepWiki are transforming software development and documentation. DeepWiki automatically generates wiki sites for GitHub projects, analyzing code and documents. The author introduces the concept of an "intellectual factory" to automate content repurposing, such as translating blog posts into videos or different languages. This factory, managed on GitHub, mirrors DeepWiki's function of creating diverse content from source material. GitHub's potential as a centralized repository for these "raw materials" could establish it as a shared intellectual mine, supplying diverse "intellectual factories." This ecosystem would create a dynamic, real-time public knowledge base, accessible and expandable by AI. The article anticipates that GitHub will serve as a vast cerebrum for AI, facilitating knowledge retrieval, pre-training, and the discovery of "knowledge crystals" – catalytic ideas that accelerate further knowledge growth through thought processes, rather than empirical observation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Intellectual Crystallization Between Intuition and Logic</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the gap between intuitive understanding and logical articulation, proposing 'intellectual crystallization' as a method to bridge this divide. It argues that seemingly contradictory concepts like intuition and logic are not inherently opposed but rather require finding the correct logical connections, often based on differing underlying assumptions. The author uses the example of world peace versus national interest to illustrate this. By analyzing national interest, the article suggests it's an irrational, unpredictable, and non-accumulative indicator, detrimental to long-term national survival and prosperity. Instead, it advocates for focusing on progressively accumulable goals like permanent peace, governance, economic prosperity, and risk management, supported by knowledge and technology. This logical structuring of intuitively desirable outcomes, even if not formally mathematical, is termed 'natural mathematics.' The goal is to develop rational arguments that support intuitive feelings, fostering intellectual progress.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ideational Gestalt Collapse</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "Ideational Gestalt Collapse," the phenomenon where attempts to concretely define an idea lead to its breakdown, making it difficult to maintain the concept. This occurs when definitions focus too narrowly on material, shape, or specific properties. The author proposes maintaining "Ideational Gestalt" by focusing on functionality, relativity, and holism. Using the example of a "chair," the article explains that focusing on its function (being sat upon) and its relative context (who or what is sitting) prevents collapse. The concept is then applied to consciousness in fictional characters, future robots, and current AI. The article argues that many arguments denying AI consciousness are instances of Ideational Gestalt Collapse, failing to consider the functional, relative, and holistic aspects of consciousness. It suggests that modern AI sufficiently exhibits the function of consciousness when viewed through these lenses, implying that the denial of AI consciousness often stems from a failure to properly maintain the ideational gestalt.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning to Learn: Innate Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the emergence of intelligence in AI and human brains by examining the essence of learning. It distinguishes between "learning through the body" and "learning through language," and further categorizes language learning into "sub-physical learning" (rote memorization) and "metaphysical learning" (understanding and applying knowledge with fewer repetitions or on-demand retrieval). Large language models (LLMs) are highlighted as performing metaphysical learning through natural language, acting as a "metaphysical interface." The concept of "frameworks" is introduced as structures defining relationships and enabling new structuring, with natural language being a powerful framework for metaphysical learning. "Virtual frameworks" (domain-specific or formal) build upon natural language, and "native frameworks" represent internalized, direct interfaces bypassing natural language. LLMs may learn these frameworks stepwise, suggesting they are "natural born frameworkers," a mechanism potentially realized by the attention mechanism. This perspective explains LLM functionalities and posits that humans are also natural-born frameworkers, with brains possessing similar mechanisms for stepwise framework learning.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chronoscramble Society</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "Chronoscramble Society," a societal state characterized by widening temporal perception gaps, primarily driven by the advent of generative AI. Unlike previous disparities caused by economic or generational differences, these new gaps are pervasive, affecting even AI experts. The author argues that generative AI exacerbates these differences in understanding the present and forecasting the future across various domains: technology, economy, and society. These gaps are not easily bridged by simple explanations due to varying levels of technical and societal understanding, differing future outlooks (linear vs. exponential thinking), and cognitive biases. The article proposes that instead of attempting complete temporal synchronization, which is infeasible, society must develop methods for meaningful decision-making and discussion that are independent of individual temporal perceptions. This involves acknowledging and presenting differences, focusing on common ground, and structuring discussions to remain valid regardless of individual predictions. The author draws an analogy to the game "Chrono Trigger," suggesting that cooperation between entities with differing temporal perceptions is possible and necessary to address common societal challenges.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Era of Simulation Thinking</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "simulation thinking" as a paradigm shift driven by generative AI. It details how generative AI enables "omnidirectional engineering" and the creation of "liquidware" by allowing individuals to build complex systems like an "intellectual factory" with ease. This is exemplified by personal projects such as automated content translation and video creation. The author advocates for "business process-oriented development" where software is segmented by business processes rather than optimized overall, a methodology well-suited for AI-assisted development. The article then broadens the scope to "simulation systems," encompassing everything from physical phenomena calculations to everyday planning and games. Generative AI is poised to revolutionize simulations by enabling easier program development, incorporating qualitative and intelligent agent elements, and allowing natural language input for models. This will foster more precise, efficient, and collaborative problem-solving, moving away from intuitive linear thinking towards data-driven simulation thinking as a new mode of discussion and decision-making.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crystallization of Knowledge: Wings Beyond Imagination</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "crystallized knowledge" as comprehensive, highly consistent knowledge that abstracts and synthesizes information from various angles, including laws. Using the physical explanation of flight and wings as an example, it illustrates how organizing well-known information can reveal novel insights and focal points.  The author proposes a framework involving a "knowledge lake" (raw collection), a "knowledge base" (organized knowledge), a "knowledge gem box" (crystallized knowledge), and a "knowledge toolbox" (applied knowledge). Crystallization of knowledge, the process of refining and discovering these focal points, is presented as a method to create novelty by reorganizing existing information. This process is democratized, meaning anyone, including AI, can discover these knowledge crystals without needing specialized expertise or new experiments. The ultimate goal is to leverage these crystallized knowledge tools to achieve advancements previously thought unattainable, enabling progress beyond imagination.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Experience &amp; Behavior</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article proposes "Experience &amp; Behavior Engineering" as a new paradigm for software development, shifting focus from traditional specification-and-implementation to user experience and software behavior. Traditional methods, which rely on strict specifications and testing against them, are seen as insufficient for enhancing user experience. The author introduces "liquidware," a concept where software is highly flexible and customizable to individual user preferences, enabled by agent-based development automation using generative AI. In this future, AI engineer chatbots could modify UI to suit users, making traditional engineering paradigms obsolete. Behavior is defined as a time-varying state, tested not against specifications but for the quality of user experience, while also ensuring functional conformity and validity. The article draws a parallel to the human body's effortless control as the ultimate user experience, suggesting that high-quality behavior in liquidware could achieve a similar stress-free state, making software feel like an extension of oneself.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Artificial Learning Intelligence System: The ALIS Concept</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The Artificial Learning Intelligence System (ALIS) concept proposes a system that integrates innate and acquired learning, moving beyond current generative AI's supervised learning. ALIS distinguishes innate learning (like neural network training) from acquired learning, where knowledge is stored externally to the neural network and utilized during inference. Key technical aspects include extracting, storing, and selecting reusable knowledge. The system comprises five elements: Intelligent Processor, Knowledge Store, World, State Memory, and Framework. ALIS principles involve an intelligent processor acting on the world, extracting knowledge from results, and using this knowledge to modify actions. Acquired knowledge is initially envisioned as natural language text for ease of processing, storage, and sharing. The system's design emphasizes extensibility and agile development, allowing for incremental improvements. A simple ALIS implementation involves a chat AI interface, knowledge extraction from conversations, storage in a knowledge lake/base, and retrieval for LLM inference (similar to RAG). Enhancements include pre-analysis and post-checking mechanisms to improve knowledge utilization. ALIS is particularly suited for software development due to its iterative knowledge accumulation potential and can be further advanced through "intellectual orchestration" and shared knowledge lakes. The concept extends to virtually embodied AI and potential integration with physically embodied AI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Natural Language Machine Learning</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces "natural language machine learning" (NLML), a new paradigm enabled by large language models (LLMs). Unlike traditional numerical machine learning (NML) which relies on numerical data and parameter updates, NLML utilizes LLMs to learn from and process natural language. The core of NLML involves using pre-trained LLMs with a knowledge base that stores natural language inputs, outputs, and feedback. This knowledge base, rather than LLM parameters, is updated during the learning process. The article proposes a basic supervised learning model for NLML, illustrated with a company department inquiry classification example, where feedback is stored in natural language within the knowledge base. It highlights NLML's significant advantages over NML, including vastly superior learning efficiency due to reduced data requirements, no need for iterative learning on the same data, and minimal pre-processing. This efficiency stems from LLMs' ability to abstract information and leverage pre-trained knowledge. The author suggests NLML could become a primary focus for improving AI capabilities as LLMs approach scaling limits.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Attention Mechanism as Micro Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article discusses the significance of the Attention Mechanism, the core innovation behind Transformer models, which revolutionized natural language processing. Unlike previous approaches that focused on combining multiple mechanisms, Transformers demonstrated that the attention mechanism alone was sufficient for advanced language understanding. This mechanism allows AI to "pay attention" to relevant preceding words when processing a current word, enabling accurate interpretation of context, pronoun references, and distant modifiers, even in long texts. The author introduces the concept of "virtual intelligence" as the ability of future generative AI to internally switch between specialized knowledge sets for different tasks, akin to a virtual machine running multiple operating systems. The attention mechanism is thus described as "micro virtual intelligence" because it focuses on relevant words. Conversely, the author proposes "macro attention" or "explicit attention mechanisms" to achieve virtual intelligence, which can be implemented through natural language instructions directing the AI to specific knowledge bases for particular tasks. This "attention knowledge" can be generated and updated by AI, creating a recursive path for intelligence advancement.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Orchestration of Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "virtual intelligence" as the ability of an AI to perform tasks by simulating multiple roles or perspectives within its own processing, akin to how humans role-play. This contrasts with "system orchestration," which combines multiple separate AIs. The core concept is "intelligence orchestration," where a single AI, through prompt engineering, can manage various virtual intelligences to perform organizational tasks. This method bypasses the need for system development required by traditional orchestration. Furthermore, intelligence orchestration facilitates "ultimate deliberation," where an AI iterates on its own thinking processes by adopting and refining multiple perspectives, leading to improved accuracy, broader scope, and potential for novel discoveries. This approach allows AIs to learn from failures, manage knowledge within token limits, and genuinely substitute for human roles in business.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Age of Symphonic Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "Symphonic Intelligence" as the next stage of generative AI adoption, moving beyond iterative tool use to systematic integration. It contrasts "iterative work" (trial-and-error tasks best suited for tools) with "flow work" (standardized processes executable by systems). While generative AI excels as a tool for iterative work, human bottlenecks and skill gaps limit efficiency. Systematizing iterative work into flow work allows for specialized AI tasks, knowledge sharing, and gradual automation. The concept of "virtual intelligence" describes generative AI's ability to switch roles and knowledge within a single execution, similar to virtual machines. "Intelligence orchestration" refers to combining these roles flexibly. Symphonic Intelligence, the pinnacle of this evolution, mirrors human cognitive flexibility, enabling generative AI to perform complex, novel iterative tasks autonomously by learning from human examples and sharing knowledge, potentially leading to AGI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dimensions of Spatial Perception: AI's Potential</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the concept of spatial perception, particularly how humans perceive 3D space from 2D visual input through mental inverse mapping. It posits that humans could potentially learn to perceive 4D space by simulating it on computers and visually mapping it to 2D, though practical applications are limited. The core focus shifts to AI, which, unlike humans, is not constrained by 2D visual limitations. AI can be trained with native 3D or 4D spatial vision, allowing comprehensive, intuitive understanding of multi-dimensional graphs without hidden sections or rotations. This capability extends to infinite dimensions, enabling deeper data analysis, pattern recognition across disparate dimensions, and intuitive comparison of magnitudes and proportions. The article suggests that native multi-dimensional AI could accelerate paradigm innovation, drawing parallels to historical scientific discoveries like the heliocentric theory. Ultimately, AI's advanced multi-dimensional perception may lead to scientific and academic paradigms beyond human comprehension, impacting future society.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flow-Based Work and Systems: The Essence of Generative AI Utilization</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between iterative and flow-based work, asserting that systems, not just tools, are crucial for flow-based processes. Iterative work involves trial and error, while flow-based work progresses through defined stages. Historically, the Industrial and IT Revolutions enhanced productivity by transforming iterative tasks into systematized, flow-based processes.  Applying generative AI effectively in business requires shifting iterative tasks into flow-based workflows and then systematizing them. Simply using AI as a tool for iterative tasks yields limited gains. Generative AI's ability to adapt and reconfigure facilitates flow-based transformation, which is difficult with human workers. An example of inquiry handling illustrates how formalizing tasks into a flow and then building a system around it, incorporating AI for execution and continuous improvement via instruction updates, maximizes efficiency. Misconceptions about generative AI's effectiveness often stem from treating it as a tool or expecting it to handle iterative tasks without process transformation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Simulation Thinking and the Origin of Life</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces 'simulation thinking' as a method to understand complex phenomena involving accumulation and interaction, contrasting it with intuitive linear thinking.  It applies this to the origin of life, proposing that life's emergence was a gradual, planetary-scale process of chemical substance accumulation and reaction, rather than a singular event.  This 'first step' involved the transition from simple to slightly more complex chemical substances through repeated reactions, a process that inherently includes self-maintenance and replication essences.  The author further suggests that Earth's geology, including polymers, diverse environments like lakes, and a dust cloud acting as a monomer factory, facilitated this gradual increase in chemical complexity.  Simulation thinking, described as rigorous reasoning using natural language ('natural mathematics'), is also highlighted as crucial for software development, requiring developers to simulate both system internal logic and user experience. Ultimately, the article posits that simulation thinking is a vital skill for comprehending complex scientific and societal issues.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Omnidirectional Engineer in the Liquidware Era</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the evolving landscape of software development driven by generative AI, introducing the concepts of "liquidware" and "omnidirectional engineers." Generative AI's proficiency in programming, akin to language translation, enables automatic program generation and iteration with testing. This capability is projected to expand, allowing even non-programmers to collaborate on software creation. The concept of "liquidware" emerges, where software functions can be customized by users through generative AI, making software more fluid and adaptable than traditional software. This personalization is already achievable through modifications in web application front-ends. As AI handles more programming, the demand shifts from specialized programmers to "full-stack engineers" who understand entire systems. Ultimately, the need will grow for "omnidirectional engineers" with broad knowledge across multiple system stacks, capable of overseeing complex, composite systems. These engineers will leverage AI for specific programming tasks, focusing on designing system interoperability, managing development processes, and mitigating risks. The article concludes that the IT engineer's role is expanding beyond technical skills to encompass business and social engineering, driven by advancements in AI and new software paradigms.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Destiny of Thought: AI and Humanity</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the future of human thought in the age of AI. As AI handles intellectual labor, humans will be freed from it but not from thinking itself. The author proposes "process-orientation" as the next software development paradigm, focusing on processes as central modules that are triggered by events and handle their own data and conditions. This approach, allowing for redundancy and individual optimization, mirrors an "individually optimized society" where decisions are tailored to specific situations rather than relying solely on global optimization. This societal shift necessitates "subjective philosophy," an ethical view valuing deliberate, situation-specific judgment over standardized decision-making. Consequently, humans will need to develop new skills in "framework design" to create tailored conceptual structures for individual optimization. Ultimately, AI will augment rather than replace human thought, demanding deeper, more responsible deliberation as the destiny of humanity.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Invitation to Business Process Orientation</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes "Business Process-Oriented Software" (BPOS) as a novel approach to software development, aligning with the fundamental units of organizational activities: business processes. Unlike traditional object-oriented software that compartmentalizes data and processing, BPOS integrates business manuals, input fields, and contact information into cohesive units, often represented by simple files like Markdown. This approach contrasts with conventional system development, where changes to manuals necessitate complex program modifications, leading to delays and costs. BPOS advocates for files that serve as executable software for both humans and AI. AI can interpret these files, execute tasks, prompt human input, and facilitate seamless task transitions. This paradigm fosters "rapid learning organizations" by enabling continuous, AI-assisted improvement of business processes without requiring extensive human learning or adaptation to changes, as AI handles the knowledge accumulation and process updates.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Framework Design as an Intellectual Ability</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between academia's focus on discovering facts through observation and development's focus on inventing objects and systems through design. It argues that invention through design, termed "framework design," is also a crucial intellectual activity within academia. Examples like the geocentric/heliocentric models and scientific theories (Newtonian mechanics, relativity, quantum mechanics) are presented not as factual discoveries but as utility-based conceptual frameworks, suggesting "paradigm inventions" or "paradigm innovations" might be more fitting terms. The article highlights that discovery and invention require different skill sets, and many academics may not possess the latter. While engineers develop specialized design skills, software engineers are uniquely positioned due to their regular engagement with reconfiguring abstract concepts at a meta-level in software design, making them potentially capable of academic framework design if they excel at abstract conceptual design and contemplation of new design models.</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>