<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Articles (en)</title>
<link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/rss.xml</link>
<description>Latest articles (en)</description>
<item>
  <title>Time Compression and Blind Spots: The Need for Regulation</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_16_Time-Compression-Blindspot/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_16_Time-Compression-Blindspot/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article discusses the accelerating pace of AI development, particularly generative AI, and its implications. This acceleration creates "time compression," where technological progress outpaces society's ability to understand and adapt, leading to "societal blind spots." Developers and the public struggle to grasp the full scope of AI's applications and impacts, creating a divergence in perceptions about the current state and future trajectory of technology. This phenomenon is termed "Chronos-Scramble Society." The author argues that gradual technological progress allows for the mitigation of risks, but rapid acceleration exacerbates them. To navigate this, the article proposes "vision" (e.g., ensuring benefits outweigh risks) and "strategy." A key strategy involves leveraging AI itself as a "built-in stabilizer" to regulate its own development, acting as a countermeasure to overheating and excessive acceleration, similar to economic stabilizers.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GitHub as an Intellectual Mine</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores GitHub's potential to evolve beyond a software development platform into a central hub for open knowledge sharing, acting as an "intellectual mine." Generative AI tools like Devin and DeepWiki are transforming software development and documentation, automating tasks like wiki generation. GitHub is already used for managing various documents, including blogs and website content. The author introduces the concept of an "intellectual factory" where AI automates the creation of diverse content from original material. This factory concept, when applied broadly, encompasses services like DeepWiki. GitHub, by hosting diverse "raw materials" for these intellectual factories, is poised to become a shared global resource. This ecosystem aims to create a dynamic, AI-accessible public knowledge base, where new insights and "intellectual crystals" – knowledge with a catalytic effect – can be discovered and disseminated at an unprecedented pace, accelerating human-driven innovation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Intellectual Crystallization Between Intuition and Logic</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "intellectual crystallization" as the process of logically articulating intuitive insights. Often, we have a feeling that something is correct but struggle to explain it, leading to communication breakdowns and the dismissal of valid ideas as subjective. This essay argues that intuition and logic are not contradictory but rather require a bridging explanation.  It proposes that differences in assumptions, objectives, or hypotheses underlie seemingly logical opposing views.  The author uses the example of "national interest" versus "world peace" to illustrate intellectual crystallization.  National interest, often presented as advantageous for a country, is deconstructed as unpredictable, rhetorical for war, and lacking progressive accumulation. In contrast, pursuing permanent peace, governance, economic prosperity, and risk management, through accumulating knowledge and technology, is presented as a rational, long-term strategy. This logical framework, expressed in natural language and possessing a "mathematical structure," is termed "natural mathematics." Discovering these intellectual crystallizations allows for opinions that are both intuitively resonant and logically sound, representing intellectual progress.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ideational Gestalt Collapse</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces the concept of "Ideational Gestalt Collapse," a phenomenon where attempting to concretely define an idea causes it to break down. The author uses the example of a "chair" to illustrate how focusing on material or shape leads to collapse, while focusing on functionality, relativity, and holism (i.e., the function of being sat upon, its context with a sitter, and its role in a larger system) helps maintain the idea. The article then applies this concept to consciousness, particularly in fictional characters and AI. It argues that denying AI consciousness based on lack of specific biological components or probabilistic output mechanisms is akin to denying a cardboard box is a chair. Instead, consciousness, like the idea of a chair, should be understood through its functionality, relativity, and wholeness. The author suggests that current AI sufficiently exhibits these aspects, implying that the denial of AI consciousness often stems from Ideational Gestalt Collapse rather than valid reasoning.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning to Learn: Innate Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the essence of learning, proposing that both artificial intelligence and human brains possess an innate tendency to learn how to learn, termed 'natural born frameworkers'. It differentiates between 'sub-physical learning' (memorization through repetition, like physical actions or rote learning) and 'metaphysical learning' (acquiring knowledge efficiently by relating it to pre-existing concepts). Natural language is presented as a key 'metaphysical interface' enabling metaphysical learning through language, distinct from traditional numerical machine learning. The article introduces 'virtual frameworks' (domain-specific or formal frameworks like math formulas or programming languages) built upon natural language, and 'native frameworks' which are internalized and bypass explicit explanation. The attention mechanism in large language models is identified as the technology realizing the 'natural born frameworker' by abstracting and clarifying relationships between tokens, enabling dynamic framework switching. This framework learning model explains LLMs' capabilities and suggests humans are also 'natural born frameworkers', with brains equipped for stepwise framework acquisition and adaptation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chronoscramble Society</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "Chronoscramble Society," a phenomenon where generative AI, particularly large language models, causes significant and widening differences in people's temporal perceptions. Unlike previous disparities rooted in economics, culture, or generation, these new gaps are not easily bridged and even AI experts hold differing views on the technology's state and future. These temporal perception differences extend beyond AI technology to its applications, economic impacts, and societal effects. The author highlights how varied access to advanced AI models, prompt engineering skills, and feature experiences create diverging understandings of AI capabilities. Future outlooks are further "hyperscrambled" due to exponential technological changes, compounding effects, network effects, and cognitive biases in predicting positive or negative outcomes. Bridging these gaps requires extensive education across technology, economics, and societal structures, and an understanding of non-linear thinking. The article proposes focusing on independence from temporal perception in decision-making and discussions, acknowledging gaps rather than aiming for complete synchronization, and focusing on areas where differences are unavoidable. The author draws an analogy to the game "Chrono Trigger," where disparate entities cooperate against a common enemy, suggesting a similar need for cooperation in society despite temporal perception differences.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Era of Simulation Thinking</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "Simulation Thinking" as a new paradigm shift enabled by generative AI. The author describes "omnidirectional engineering" and "liquidware" facilitated by AI in software development, allowing for highly customizable and fluid software.  This includes the creation of "intellectual factories" for automated content generation.  In business systems, AI supports "business process-oriented development," emphasizing modularity over overall optimization.  More broadly, generative AI transforms simulation systems across disciplines like physics, biology, and economics, enabling qualitative simulations, natural language modeling, and human-like intelligent agents.  These AI-powered simulations can aid in decision-making, improve the precision of discussions by providing objective models, and shift thinking from linear intuition to data-driven simulation.  The author posits that this will lead to more constructive discourse, focusing on model evaluation rather than individual arguments.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crystallization of Knowledge: Wings Beyond Imagination</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "crystallized knowledge," defined as comprehensive and highly consistent knowledge that abstractly integrates multiple pieces of information from various angles, including laws. Using the physical explanation of flight and wings as an example, it illustrates how organizing existing knowledge can reveal novel viewpoints and focal points, which constitutes the crystallization of knowledge. The author proposes a hierarchy of knowledge organization: a "knowledge lake" for raw, unorganized knowledge; a "knowledge base" for organized documented knowledge; a "knowledge gem box" for crystallized knowledge; and a "knowledge toolbox" for practical applications derived from crystallized knowledge. The article emphasizes that discovering crystallized knowledge doesn't require new scientific discovery but rather the adept organization and refinement of existing knowledge, a process accessible to anyone, including AI, thereby democratizing knowledge creation and enabling future advancements.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Experience &amp; Behavior</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes a new engineering paradigm, "Experience &amp; Behavior Engineering," contrasting it with traditional "specifications-and-implementation-based engineering." It argues that as user experience (UX) becomes paramount, the focus should shift from implementation to user behavior. The concept of "liquidware" is introduced, describing software that can be infinitely customized to individual user preferences, enabled by generative AI and AI engineer chatbots. This flexibility challenges the rigid structure of current development. Behavior is defined as a time-varying state, tested not against specifications but against the quality of the user's experience, including functional correctness. The ultimate user experience is likened to effortless control of one's own healthy body, suggesting that highly flexible liquidware could offer a similarly stress-free interaction, effectively extending our capabilities as if it were a part of ourselves.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Artificial Learning Intelligence System: The ALIS Concept</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The Artificial Learning Intelligence System (ALIS) concept integrates innate learning (like neural network training) with acquired learning, where knowledge is stored externally and utilized during inference. ALIS comprises five elements: Intelligent Processor, Knowledge Store, World, State Memory, and Framework. Learning occurs as the processor acts on the world, extracts knowledge, and stores it. Acquired knowledge is proposed to be textualized natural language for ease of processing, storage, and sharing. Formal languages and models can also be used for rigorous reasoning. ALIS development follows an agile, incremental approach, starting with a basic chat AI and knowledge lake, then adding pre-analysis and post-checking mechanisms for improved knowledge utilization. Potential applications include software development, with possibilities for open sharing and further LLM pre-training. ALIS exhibits virtually embodied AI characteristics through its interaction with a defined 'world' and has the potential to integrate with physical embodied AI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Natural Language Machine Learning</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces natural language machine learning (NLML), a new paradigm that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) for learning through language, contrasting it with traditional numerical machine learning. NLML utilizes pre-trained LLMs, where the learning process involves updating a knowledge base with natural language data rather than modifying LLM parameters. A basic model is presented, akin to supervised learning for classification, where input sentences and teacher-judged outputs are stored. A more realistic scenario involves a human-in-the-loop system for routing inquiries, where corrected routes are fed back into the knowledge base. NLML boasts superior learning efficiency, requiring less data, no iterative learning, and minimal pre-processing compared to numerical methods, thanks to LLMs' abstractive capabilities. While LLMs are slower in processing, the learning efficiency gains are substantial. The article suggests NLML may become a primary focus for future capability improvements as LLMs approach scaling limits.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Attention Mechanism as Micro Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the Attention Mechanism, a core component of Transformer models, as a "micro virtual intelligence."  This mechanism allows AI to dynamically focus on relevant preceding words when processing new words, crucial for understanding context, co-reference, and long-range dependencies in natural language. The author introduces "virtual intelligence" as the ability of future generative AI to internally switch between specialized knowledge sets for complex tasks, akin to a virtual machine running multiple operating systems. The Attention Mechanism is likened to this but operates on words rather than knowledge sets. The article proposes an "explicit attention mechanism" which uses natural language instructions to guide AI's knowledge focus, suggesting this macro-level attention can be managed by generative AI itself, thereby enabling recursive advancement of intelligence across different layers.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Orchestration of Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "virtual intelligence" as the ability of an AI to simulate multiple personas or roles within its processing, akin to how humans use virtual intelligence in daily life and how conversational AI currently demonstrates this. It proposes "intelligence orchestration" as a method to combine multiple virtual intelligences within a single AI, analogous to system orchestration using virtual machines. Unlike system orchestration, intelligence orchestration requires no system development, only prompt instructions, allowing for flexible role switching and task execution. This method enables "ultimate deliberation" by instructing AI to combine multiple perspectives and iterate on its own thinking processes, leading to improved accuracy, broader scope, and potential for new discoveries. Ultimately, intelligence orchestration allows a single AI to perform advanced organizational intellectual activities, accumulate knowledge from failures, and genuinely substitute for human roles in business.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Age of Symphonic Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "Symphonic Intelligence" as the next stage of generative AI, moving beyond simple tool integration to systematic application. It contrasts "iterative work," where AI acts as a tool for trial-and-error tasks limited by human bottlenecks, with "flow work," where tasks are standardized and systematized. Transforming iterative work into systematized flow work allows for specialized AI tasks, knowledge sharing, and gradual automation. The concept of "virtual intelligence" describes AI's ability to switch roles and knowledge within a single execution, analogous to virtual machines. "Intelligence orchestration" is the skill to manage these roles and knowledge flexibly. Symphonic Intelligence, the ultimate goal, is AI capable of orchestrating these capabilities, mimicking human intelligence's flexibility in iterative tasks. This stage, when AI can autonomously learn and adapt to new tasks through observation, represents a form of AGI, surpassing human learning capacity through shared knowledge accumulation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dimensions of Spatial Perception: AI's Potential</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the concept of multi-dimensional spatial perception, drawing a parallel between human visual processing and artificial intelligence (AI). Humans perceive 3D space from 2D retinal images by inverse-mapping onto an internal 3D spatial model, a principle that could theoretically allow humans to perceive 4D space via computer simulation and inverse mapping. However, practical application for humans is limited. AI, unconstrained by 2D visual limitations, can be trained with native N-dimensional vision. This allows AI to natively grasp N-dimensional graphs without hidden sections or rotations, facilitating intuitive understanding of complex data, trend analysis, and pattern recognition across dimensions. This capability can accelerate scientific discovery and paradigm innovation, potentially leading to theories like relativity or quantum mechanics being realized sooner. While AI may simplify high-dimensional concepts for human understanding, the sheer volume of new paradigms could exceed human comprehension, leading to a future where humans use advanced systems without fully understanding their underlying principles.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flow-Based Work and Systems: The Essence of Generative AI Utilization</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between iterative and flow-based work, arguing that true value from generative AI in business comes from transforming iterative tasks into systematized, flow-based processes. While AI can act as a tool for iterative tasks, its potential is limited. The author posits that generative AI, unlike humans, can more readily adapt to reconfigured tasks, making it ideal for flow-based transformations that were difficult to achieve with human workers alone. Examples like the Industrial and IT Revolutions highlight how systematizing transformed iterative work boosts productivity. The article provides a detailed example of handling employee inquiries, showing how to shift from using AI as a tool for isolated tasks to integrating it into a formalized workflow for comprehensive inquiry management, including drafting answers, updating FAQs, and process refinement. Common misconceptions about generative AI's limited effectiveness stem from viewing it solely as a tool for iterative tasks or expecting current AI to perfectly execute complex iterative duties. The key to unlocking generative AI's potential lies in this shift towards flow-based systematization and continuous improvement.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Simulation Thinking and the Origin of Life</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "simulation thinking" as a method to understand complex phenomena by tracing accumulation and interaction, exemplified by a simple allowance problem. This thinking is applied to the origin of life, proposing it as a gradual, planet-wide accumulation and interaction of chemical substances, rather than a singular miracle. The process involves the Earth transitioning from simple chemicals to more complex ones through repeated reactions, supported by factors like polymer formation, diverse environments in lakes/ponds, and a "monomer factory" created by dust clouds blocking UV radiation and acting as catalysts. This planetary-scale, step-by-step process, enhanced by Earth's geology and atmospheric conditions, forms the essence of life. The author contrasts this with formal computer simulations, advocating for "natural mathematics" and simulation thinking using natural language to grasp such complex processes. The article highlights software development as a field that heavily relies on this dual simulation thinking (system internal workings and customer intent), suggesting its broader applicability in understanding complex systems in society.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Omnidirectional Engineer in the Liquidware Era</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article discusses the transformative impact of generative AI on software development, introducing the concepts of "liquidware" and "omnidirectional engineers." Generative AI's ability to write code and iterate based on test results is automating programming tasks. This leads to the concept of liquidware, where software can be customized by users through AI, making it fluid and adaptable. This shifts development from fixed software to user-defined modifications. Consequently, the demand for "full-stack engineers" is evolving into a need for "omnidirectional engineers" who possess broad knowledge across multiple system stacks and can manage complex, multi-platform, and multi-device software development, often integrating various services and AI tools. These engineers will orchestrate development by defining procedures and mechanisms, leveraging AI for specific programming tasks, and focusing on overall system design and interoperability. The article posits that this trend will extend to omnidirectional business and social engineering.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Destiny of Thought: AI and Humanity</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article posits that advancements in AI will not eliminate human thinking but rather shift its focus. Just as mechanization freed humans from physical labor, AI will free us from intellectual labor, demanding new forms of thought. The author proposes a paradigm shift in software development from object-orientation to process-orientation, where processes, triggered by events and involving roles, are central modules. This approach aligns with human intuition and allows for greater flexibility, especially with AI assistance in programming, potentially leading to redundancy for individual optimization. This societal shift mirrors an "individually optimized society" where global optimization gives way to case-by-case judgments, allowing for unique circumstances. This necessitates a "subjective philosophy" where the act of deliberation and taking responsibility for individual judgments is paramount. Consequently, humans will need enhanced skills in framework design to handle these nuanced, individualized evaluations, ultimately leading to a future where continuous, deep thinking is not just necessary but expected.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Invitation to Business Process Orientation</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes "Business Process-Oriented Software" as a new approach to software development, analogous to object-oriented software. This concept bundles related data and processing within the conceptual unit of a business process, aligning with human perception for easier modification and feature addition. Unlike traditional systems that separate manuals from processing, this approach integrates business manuals, input fields, and contact information into a single file, which itself functions as executable software for both humans and AI. AI can assist in executing these files by reading manuals, performing tasks, prompting human input, and managing file transfers. Markdown files are suggested for AI readability. This methodology facilitates rapid knowledge accumulation and continuous improvement, enabling organizations to become "rapid learning organizations" where AI handles the complexities of learning and adapting to changing business processes, freeing humans from extensive manual learning.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Framework Design as an Intellectual Ability</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between academic discovery through observation and development through design. While academia typically focuses on discovering facts and development on creating new systems, some academic fields, like engineering, blend both. The author argues that framework design, exemplified by scientific models like geocentric vs. heliocentric or Newtonian mechanics vs. relativity, is a crucial intellectual activity within academia. These frameworks are not about correctness but utility, offering choices rather than singular truths. The article posits that paradigm shifts are better understood as paradigm inventions or innovations, increasing useful options. While discovery and invention require different skill sets, and most academics excel at discovery, software engineers are uniquely positioned to perform framework design due to their regular engagement with reconfiguring abstract concepts at a meta-level in software design. Developing a habit of contemplating new design models further enhances suitability for academic framework design.</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>