<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Articles (en)</title>
<link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/rss.xml</link>
<description>Latest articles (en)</description>
<item>
  <title>GitHub as an Intellectual Mine</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores GitHub's potential as a future intellectual mine and a shared global knowledge base. It discusses how generative AI, exemplified by tools like Devin and DeepWiki, is transforming software development and documentation. DeepWiki automatically generates wiki sites for GitHub projects, demonstrating AI's capability to analyze and synthesize information. The article posits that GitHub, already a platform for collaborative code and document sharing, can evolve into a central repository for raw materials for "intellectual factories" – systems that use generative AI to create diverse content formats from original works. The author's "intellectual factory" concept, which automates content repurposing like translation and video creation, parallels DeepWiki's function. GitHub's expansion as a document platform, including prompts for generative AI, positions it as an "intellectual mine" supplying data for these factories. This ecosystem fosters a dynamic, AI-utilizable knowledge base, potentially accelerating discovery of "intellectual crystals" – catalytic knowledge promoting further innovation, akin to mathematical inquiry rather than scientific observation.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Intellectual Crystallization Between Intuition and Logic</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the gap between intuition and logical explanation, proposing 'intellectual crystallization' as a method to bridge this divide. It argues that seemingly contradictory views, particularly concerning national interest versus world peace, can be reconciled through logical frameworks by examining underlying assumptions, objectives, and hypotheses. The author uses the example of national interest to illustrate how prioritizing long-term survival and prosperity through accumulable knowledge and technology, rather than the unpredictable and rhetoric-prone 'national interest,' is a more rational strategy. This analytical approach, termed 'natural mathematics,' involves identifying objective logical models that can be expressed in natural language. By uncovering these mathematical structures within intuitive insights, one can construct arguments that are both intuitively resonant and logically sound, representing a step forward in intellectual progress.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ideational Gestalt Collapse</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of "Ideational Gestalt Collapse," a phenomenon where attempts to concretely define an idea lead to its breakdown. The author uses the example of a "chair" to illustrate how focusing on material or shape can cause collapse, while focusing on functionality, relativity, and holism can maintain the concept. This framework is then applied to the complex notion of consciousness, particularly in fictional characters and future AI. The article argues that many denials of AI consciousness are based on superficial arguments akin to denying a chair's existence due to a lack of legs. Instead, it suggests maintaining the ideational gestalt of consciousness by considering its functionality, relativity, and wholeness, arguing that current AI exhibits these aspects sufficiently to warrant a discussion about its consciousness. The core argument is that current denials of AI consciousness often represent an "Ideational Gestalt Collapse" rather than valid reasoning.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning to Learn: Innate Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the essence of learning, proposing that both humans and artificial intelligence possess an innate "natural born frameworker" mechanism for learning how to learn. It distinguishes between "sub-physical learning" (rote memorization through repetition) and "metaphysical learning" (utilizing existing knowledge to learn new concepts efficiently, often with fewer repetitions or by referencing external information). Natural language is identified as a key "metaphysical interface," enabling metaphysical learning through language, unlike traditional machine learning which primarily relies on sub-physical learning. The concept of "frameworks" is introduced as structures that define relationships between concepts, with natural language serving as a foundational framework. "Virtual frameworks" (domain-specific or formal frameworks like mathematical formulas) build upon natural language, and "native frameworks" are internalized versions of these, bypassing explicit language explanation. The attention mechanism in large language models is highlighted as the technological enabler of this stepwise framework learning, making LLMs "natural born frameworkers." This framework-based learning can explain the emergent abilities of LLMs and suggests humans are also natural-born frameworkers, with natural language evolving to facilitate efficient framework acquisition.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chronoscramble Society</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of a "Chronoscramble Society," a societal state characterized by widening temporal perception gaps, largely driven by the advent of generative AI. Unlike previous temporal disparities rooted in economic or generational differences, the AI-driven gaps are more profound, affecting even AI experts and extending beyond technological proficiency to applied AI, system technologies, economic impacts, and societal consequences. These differences stem from varying access to information, differing abilities in estimating AI capabilities (e.g., prompt engineering, specific AI model usage), and diverse future outlooks influenced by linear vs. exponential thinking and cognitive biases. Bridging these gaps requires more than simple explanations; it necessitates comprehensive education across technology, economics, and societal structures, as well as addressing cognitive biases. The author argues that aiming for complete temporal synchronicity is unrealistic. Instead, decision-making should focus on achieving "independence from temporal perception," acknowledging and presenting differences, and focusing discussions on unavoidable areas of divergence to ensure meaningful dialogue and effective decision-making in a permanently "scrambled" temporal reality.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Era of Simulation Thinking</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "Simulation Thinking" as a paradigm shift driven by generative AI. The author details personal experiences creating an "intellectual factory" using generative AI for content derivation and an "omnidirectional engineering" approach for system development, resulting in "liquidware" that is flexible and personalized. In business systems, a "business process-oriented development" methodology is proposed, segmenting software by process rather than optimizing globally, which is facilitated by AI-driven program generation. The article extends this to "simulation systems," which encompass everything from scientific calculations to everyday decision-making. Generative AI's ability to easily create simulation programs, incorporate qualitative elements, and use natural language for models allows for more accurate and collaborative problem-solving. This move from linear thinking to simulation thinking, where AI assists in building and running simulations based on discussions, is presented as the future of deliberation and decision-making.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crystallization of Knowledge: Wings Beyond Imagination</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article defines "crystallized knowledge" as comprehensive, consistent, and abstractly integrated information, using the physical explanation of flight and wings as an example. It explains how wings facilitate flight by managing air resistance, converting force direction, and generating airflow differentials, enabling gliding, utilizing external energy (updrafts, headwinds), and self-generated energy (rotary blades, propellers, flapping). The author posits that novelty in knowledge lies not in discovering new scientific principles but in organizing and associating existing knowledge to reveal focal points. This process of refinement is termed "crystallization of knowledge."  The article introduces a framework: "knowledge lake" (raw, unorganized knowledge), "knowledge base" (organized documented knowledge), "knowledge gem box" (crystallized knowledge), and "knowledge toolbox" (applied, practical knowledge).  It emphasizes that discovering knowledge crystals requires no specialized expertise or experimentation, suggesting a democratization of knowledge, making it accessible to anyone, including AI, to create novel applications and advancements.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Experience &amp; Behavior</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes "Experience &amp; Behavior Engineering" as a new paradigm for software development, shifting focus from specifications and implementation to user experience and software behavior. Traditional methods are insufficient as they prioritize adherence to predefined specifications. The author argues that user experience is shaped by software behavior, which is defined as a state that changes over time. Behavior testing should evaluate the quality of user experience, including functional conformity and validity, and go beyond mere specification alignment. The advent of generative AI and agent-based development could enable "liquidware" – software that is highly flexible and adapts to individual user preferences, akin to a perfectly controlled human body. This liquidware would represent an extension of our own capabilities, marking a departure from the outdated specifications-and-implementation engineering model.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Artificial Learning Intelligence System: The ALIS Concept</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces the Artificial Learning Intelligence System (ALIS) concept, which integrates innate learning (neural network training) with acquired learning. Acquired learning involves externally storing and utilizing reusable knowledge, with a core focus on extraction, storage, selection, and utilization. ALIS is presented as a system technology combining these learning processes.  It defines five elements: Intelligent Processor, Knowledge Store, World, State Memory, and Framework. The principle involves the processor acting on the world, learning from results, and refining actions. Acquired knowledge is proposed to be textualized in natural language for ease of use and sharing. The system can also leverage formal languages. The article outlines a basic design starting with a chat AI, adding knowledge extraction, storage (knowledge lake/base), and RAG-like utilization. Improvements include pre-analysis and post-checking to enhance knowledge selection. ALIS is seen as ideal for software development and has the potential for 'intellectual orchestration' by segmenting knowledge stores. Future applications extend to various intellectual activities and potentially physical embodied AI, with emphasis on agile, incremental development.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Natural Language Machine Learning</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces "natural language machine learning" (NLML) as a new paradigm that leverages large language models (LLMs) for learning, contrasting it with traditional numerical machine learning. While LLM pre-training uses numerical methods, NLML utilizes pre-trained LLMs to learn from natural language data. A basic model is presented where an LLM, without parameter changes, classifies input sentences based on a knowledge base updated by a teacher system judging its responses. A more realistic scenario involves humans or systems feeding routing logs into a knowledge base, which then guides the LLM. The core innovation is that learning updates the knowledge base with natural language, not LLM parameters. NLML boasts superior learning efficiency, requiring significantly less data, no iterative training, and minimal pre-processing compared to numerical methods, as LLMs can abstract and consolidate information from single sentences across multiple dimensions. This efficiency is seen as a crucial advantage, potentially guiding future AI development beyond simple LLM scaling.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Attention Mechanism as Micro Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article explores the Attention Mechanism, central to the Transformer architecture, which revolutionized natural language processing by allowing AI to focus on relevant preceding words. This "attention" enables accurate understanding of context, pronoun resolution, and long-range dependencies. The author introduces "virtual intelligence" as the ability of AI to internally switch between specialized knowledge sets for different tasks, analogous to virtual machines. The Attention Mechanism is then framed as "micro virtual intelligence" due to its word-level focus on relevant information. Conversely, "virtual intelligence" can be implemented as a "macro attention mechanism" through explicit natural language instructions directing AI to specific knowledge bases for given tasks. This "explicit attention mechanism" can be generated and updated by AI itself, suggesting a path for recursively advancing intelligence across different layers.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Orchestration of Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces "virtual intelligence" as the ability of a single AI to embody multiple roles within its processing, akin to humans role-playing. It contrasts this with "system orchestration" which uses virtual machines to combine separate AI systems. "Intelligence orchestration" leverages virtual intelligence to combine multiple AI roles within a single AI model for organizational tasks, requiring only prompt instructions instead of system development. This allows for flexible role switching, easier improvements, and rapid iteration. Furthermore, intelligence orchestration enables "ultimate deliberation" by instructing AI to combine multiple perspectives and iterate on its own deliberation methods, leading to improved accuracy, broader scope, and creativity. The conclusion emphasizes that virtual intelligence and intelligence orchestration allow AI to perform advanced organizational tasks, learn from failures, manage knowledge, and act as a genuine human substitute in business settings.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Age of Symphonic Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes "Symphonic Intelligence" as the next stage of generative AI integration, moving beyond simple tool utilization to systematic integration. It analyzes current AI use through "iterative work" (task combination with tools) and "flow work" (standardized processes executed by systems). Iterative work with AI as a tool faces limitations due to human bottlenecks and the difficulty of codifying unconscious tasks. Transforming iterative work into standardized "flow work" and systemizing it allows for specialized AI tasks, shared knowledge, and gradual automation, akin to a factory line. The concept of "virtual intelligence" describes AI's ability to switch roles and knowledge within a single execution, enabling more flexible, human-like iterative work without system changes. "Intelligence orchestration" refers to the AI's skill in managing these roles and knowledge. Symphonic Intelligence, characterized by AI's ability to perform complex intellectual tasks flexibly, is presented as the ultimate goal, mirroring human intelligence. This stage, a potential form of AGI, will allow AI to learn new tasks automatically and share knowledge, rapidly surpassing human learning capabilities.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dimensions of Spatial Perception: AI's Potential</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes that humans, who perceive 3D space from 2D visual input via inverse mapping, could potentially learn to perceive 4D space through computer simulations. However, this ability has limited practical applications for humans. AI, conversely, can be natively trained to perceive 3D or higher-dimensional spaces. This allows AI to comprehend multi-dimensional graphs intuitively, unlike humans who face limitations with even 3D graphs. AI's multi-dimensional perception enables deeper data analysis, pattern discovery across disparate dimensions, and intuitive understanding of data structures through flexible axis manipulation. This capability has the potential to accelerate scientific paradigm innovation, akin to how easier data comprehension could have spurred earlier discoveries like the heliocentric theory. While AI will likely translate complex paradigms for human understanding, humans may eventually be unable to fully grasp all advanced concepts, living alongside systems whose principles remain comprehensible only to AI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flow-Based Work and Systems: The Essence of Generative AI Utilization</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between iterative and flow-based work, asserting that true value from generative AI in business comes from transforming iterative tasks into flow-based processes and then systematizing them. Simply using AI as a tool for iterative work yields limited efficiency gains. The author highlights the Industrial and IT Revolutions as historical examples of productivity leaps achieved through flow-based transformation and systematization. Unlike human workers, generative AI's flexibility in reconfiguring tasks makes it uniquely suited for flow-based transformation. The article provides an example of inquiry handling, detailing how to map out a flow-based process for AI integration and systematization, emphasizing continuous improvement through updated instructions and human oversight. Common misconceptions about generative AI's ineffectiveness are attributed to viewing it solely as a tool for iterative tasks, rather than a component in a systematized flow.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Simulation Thinking and the Origin of Life</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "simulation thinking" as a method to understand complex phenomena involving accumulation and interaction, exemplified by a grandchild's allowance problem. This thinking is then applied to the origin of life, proposing a gradual, planetary-scale chemical evolution from simple substances to complex polymers. The Earth's environment, including water/air circulation, diverse locations, and atmospheric dust clouds, facilitated this process, acting as a continuous monomer factory. The author argues that the initial step already embodies the essence of life, and subsequent steps involve increasingly complex self-maintenance, replication, and metabolism. Simulation thinking, termed "natural mathematics" when applied to natural language, is crucial for this understanding, enabling comprehension of trends without strict formalization. The article also highlights its importance in software development, where developers use it to translate abstract requirements into functional systems, possessing both principled and semantic simulation capabilities.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Omnidirectional Engineer in the Liquidware Era</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the evolving landscape of software development, driven by generative AI and the emerging concept of "liquidware." Generative AI is increasingly capable of programming, automating tasks previously requiring human coders. This shift enables a new paradigm called liquidware, where software can be customized by end-users through AI-driven modifications, allowing for highly personalized digital experiences. The author introduces the "omnidirectional engineer," a professional who possesses broad knowledge across various system stacks and can effectively leverage AI for development, design, and integration. This role transcends traditional full-stack engineering, emphasizing adaptability and the ability to orchestrate complex, multi-platform, multi-device software ecosystems. The article argues that becoming an omnidirectional engineer is crucial for IT professionals to remain relevant in an era of rapid technological advancement, extending beyond IT to business and social engineering.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Destiny of Thought: AI and Humanity</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article posits that as AI advances and handles intellectual labor, humanity will not cease thinking but will instead shift to a different kind of thinking. This parallels mechanization freeing humans from physical labor, leading to new forms of manual dexterity. The author proposes "process-orientation" as the next software development paradigm, focusing on sequential, event-triggered processes treated as single modules with self-contained data and conditions. This allows for individual optimization within processes, potentially leading to redundancy but offering flexibility, especially with AI assistance. This concept extends to society, creating an "individually optimized society" where judgments are tailored to specific circumstances rather than relying solely on global optimization. This shift necessitates "subjective philosophy," an ethical stance valuing deliberate, individual judgment over standardized outcomes. The ability to design frameworks for these individual optimizations will become a crucial human skill. Ultimately, AI's efficiency will free us from labor but not from thinking; instead, it will demand deeper, more individualized deliberation, making the "destiny of thought" inescapable.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Invitation to Business Process Orientation</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article proposes "Business Process-Oriented Software" (BPOS) as a new approach to software development, contrasting it with traditional object-oriented software. BPOS integrates business process manuals, input fields, and contact information into a single, cohesive unit, often a file. This unit functions as "software" executed by humans or AI. Unlike conventional systems where manuals and processing are separated, leading to complex updates and high costs, BPOS facilitates easier modifications and feature additions by treating the process manual and its associated data as one entity. AI can execute BPOS files, assisting humans by performing tasks, prompting for input, and adapting interfaces. Markdown is suggested as an AI-friendly format. This approach fosters knowledge accumulation, rapid business process improvement, and enables organizations to become "rapid learning organizations" by offloading the burden of learning and adapting to changing processes onto AI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Framework Design as an Intellectual Ability</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article distinguishes between academic discovery through observation and developmental invention through design. While academia traditionally focuses on discovering facts, the article posits that invention through design, particularly framework design, is also a crucial intellectual activity within academia. Examples like the geocentric vs. heliocentric models, Newtonian mechanics, relativity, and quantum mechanics are presented not as discoveries but as inventions of conceptual frameworks whose utility, not correctness, dictates their selection. These are termed paradigm inventions or innovations, offering more options rather than complete shifts. The article argues that discovery and invention require different skill sets, and while many academics excel at discovery, fewer possess design invention skills. Software engineers are highlighted as a profession that routinely reconfigures abstract concepts at a meta-level, potentially equipping them with the necessary skills for academic framework design, especially those who habitually contemplate new design models.</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>