<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katoshi&apos;s Research Notes</title>
    <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Research notes by a Software Engineer/System Architect/Ph.D. in Engineering. Exploring the mechanisms of life&apos;s origins, essence of life phenomena, and structures of intelligence and society through software development experience.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an Era Without Walls: Creating a 30-Language Blog Site</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_24_wall-free-era/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_24_wall-free-era/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article details the creation of a 30-language blog site using generative AI, specifically Google&apos;s Gemini.  The author, a system engineer, describes a system built using the Astro framework that automatically generates HTML from Japanese article drafts.  Gemini is integral, handling tasks like categorization, tagging (using APIs to interpret article meaning and suggest appropriate categories and tags), multilingual translation (both for website strings and article content), and even suggesting accessibility improvements.  The author emphasizes how Gemini overcame challenges like language barriers (supporting 30 languages), ensuring nuanced translation accuracy, handling language-specific formatting (dates, numbers, right-to-left languages), and incorporating accessibility features for visually impaired or keyboard-only users. This process, automated through custom programs, highlights the potential of generative AI to break down barriers to information dissemination, especially in multilingual and accessible website creation. The author concludes that this approach democratizes website creation, empowering individuals even without extensive programming experience to create and maintain multilingual, accessible online content. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development-Driven Development and Refactoring-Driven Testing</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_19_dev-development/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_19_dev-development/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article introduces &quot;Development-Driven Development&quot; and &quot;Refactoring-Driven Test,&quot; two novel approaches to software development leveraging generative AI.  Development-Driven Development focuses on iteratively building tools during the development process to improve efficiency and reuse assets across projects.  Refactoring-Driven Test advocates creating tests after significant development and refactoring, concentrating on stable components rather than testing all code upfront.  The author contrasts these methods with traditional Test-Driven Development, arguing that for projects involving significant UI/UX elements, prioritizing functional interaction and then testing stable sections post-refactoring is more effective. This approach, combined with the increasing role of generative AI in software development, aims to create a more efficient and adaptable software development lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Compression and Blind Spots: The Need for **調速** (Speed Regulation)</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_16_time-compression-blindspot/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_16_time-compression-blindspot/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article discusses the accelerating pace of AI technological progress, creating a &quot;Chronoscramble Society&quot; where individuals&apos; perceptions of time and technological advancement differ significantly. This rapid advancement, termed &quot;time compression,&quot; leads to &quot;social blind spots&quot;—unforeseen risks and consequences of new technologies that emerge before society can adapt. The author argues that this imbalance between technological progress and societal understanding necessitates a shift in strategy. Instead of trying to align everyone&apos;s perception of time, the focus should be on establishing immutable values and directions (vision) and employing strategies that leverage the very technology causing the problem—generative AI—to regulate its own development, acting as a &quot;built-in stabilizer&quot; to prevent uncontrolled acceleration and mitigate risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub as an Intellectual Mine</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_15_intellectual-mine-github/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_15_intellectual-mine-github/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article proposes GitHub&apos;s evolution into an &quot;Intellectual Mine,&quot; a central repository for various documents beyond software code, serving as raw material for &quot;Intellectual Factories.&quot;  These factories, utilizing generative AI, process documents from the Intellectual Mine to create diverse content formats (translations, videos, etc.).  The author uses their own blog as an example, automating content creation across multiple platforms.  DeepWiki, a service generating wiki sites from GitHub projects, is presented as a precursor to this concept.  The article envisions a future where GitHub becomes a dynamic, publicly shared knowledge base, fueled by AI-driven content generation and knowledge discovery, accelerating the creation and dissemination of knowledge, especially knowledge with a catalytic effect, which the author terms &quot;Intellectual Crystals.&quot;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Gestalt Collapse</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_14_concept-gestalt-collapse/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_14_concept-gestalt-collapse/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article introduces &quot;Idea Gestalt Collapse,&quot; a phenomenon where overanalyzing a concept leads to its breakdown.  Using the example of a &quot;chair,&quot; it argues that focusing on functionality, relativity (context-dependent function), and wholeness (the relationship between the object and its user) prevents this collapse.  The author applies this framework to the question of consciousness in fictional characters, anime robots, future robots, and current AI.  While acknowledging arguments against AI consciousness based on scientific, logical, or capability grounds, the author critiques these as examples of Idea Gestalt Collapse, arguing that current AI exhibits sufficient functionality to warrant consideration of consciousness, even without a complete scientific understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Crystals: Between Intuition and Logic</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_14_intuition-and-logic/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_14_intuition-and-logic/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article explores the disconnect between intuition and logic, arguing that intuitively felt truths should have logical explanations.  It introduces the concept of &quot;intellectual crystals&quot; – underlying mathematical structures that connect intuition and logic, illustrated by an analysis of &quot;national interest.&quot; The author challenges the reliance on national interest for long-term national survival and prosperity, arguing its unpredictability and potential for short-sighted decisions.  Instead, a focus on permanent peace, good governance, economic prosperity, and risk management, leading to &quot;progressive accumulation&quot; of knowledge and technology, is presented as a more rational long-term strategy. This strategy, unlike national interest, benefits all nations when shared. The author frames this analysis as &quot;natural mathematics,&quot; a logically sound model expressed in natural language, showcasing how intuitive truths can be supported by rigorous logic, even without formal mathematical notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Learn: Innate Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_13_natural-born-frameworker/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_13_natural-born-frameworker/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article explores the nature of intelligence in AI, proposing that both AI and human brains possess an innate ability to learn how to learn, termed &quot;Natural Born Frameworker.&quot;  It distinguishes between &quot;metacognitive learning&quot; (repetitive learning) and &quot;metaphysical learning&quot; (intuitive understanding), with natural language acting as a key interface.  Metacognitive learning builds frameworks that enable metaphysical learning.  The article introduces &quot;virtual frameworks&quot; (built upon natural language) and &quot;native frameworks&quot; (mastered to the point of intuitive use), arguing that large language models learn through a layered framework acquisition process, starting with natural language and progressing to specialized frameworks.  The &quot;attention mechanism&quot; is identified as the technology enabling this framework learning, explaining the power of large language models.  The article concludes that humans also possess this &quot;Natural Born Frameworker&quot; capacity, suggesting natural language&apos;s structure is optimized for framework learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronoscramble Society</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_12_chronoscramble-society/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_12_chronoscramble-society/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article introduces the concept of a &quot;Chronoscramble Society,&quot; where the advent of generative AI creates significant discrepancies in individuals&apos; perceptions of time, surpassing traditional divides like nationality or generation.  This disparity stems from uneven access to and understanding of AI technologies, their applications, and their societal impact.  The author argues that these temporal perception gaps are not easily bridged through simple explanations, requiring a deeper understanding of technology, economics, and societal structures, along with the ability to move beyond linear projections of future impacts.  The author further explores the complexities of future vision discrepancies, shaped by cognitive biases and varying levels of agency, making consensus and decision-making extremely challenging.  Ultimately, the article suggests that adapting to this new reality requires developing methods for meaningful discussion and decision-making that acknowledge and account for these inherent discrepancies in temporal perception, rather than striving for unattainable synchronization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Simulation Thinking</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_12_simulation-thinking-era/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_12_simulation-thinking-era/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Generative AI is revolutionizing software development and simulation. The author describes building an &quot;Intellectual Factory,&quot; a system using generative AI to create various content from original material,  and calls their full-stack development approach &quot;Omnidirectional Engineering.&quot;  They also introduce &quot;Liquidware,&quot; software easily adaptable through AI-powered programming.  Further, the author proposes a &quot;Business Process-Oriented&quot; development methodology, focusing on individual process optimization rather than overall system optimization, facilitated by AI.  This simplifies development and maintenance.  Finally, the author discusses the expanding role of generative AI in simulation systems across various fields, enabling more complex and accessible simulations. This shift towards easily created simulation systems promotes a transition from linear to &quot;Simulation Thinking,&quot; using simulations as a common ground for more objective and productive discussions and decision-making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience &amp; Behavior</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_10_experience-behavior/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_10_experience-behavior/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article contrasts traditional Specification and Implementation-Based Engineering with a proposed Experience &amp; Behavior Engineering.  Traditional methods focus on aligning implementation with pre-defined specifications, while the new paradigm prioritizes user experience shaped by software behavior.  This shift is enabled by advancements in AI-driven software development automation. The author introduces the concept of &apos;Liquidware,&apos; software adaptable to individual user preferences via AI-powered modification, becoming seamless and intuitive like controlling one&apos;s own body.  The article argues that testing in this new paradigm focuses on user experience quality, not just specification adherence, while still ensuring functional correctness. The ultimate goal is to create &apos;Liquidware&apos; so intuitive and integrated that it feels like an extension of the user&apos;s self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Crystallization: Wings Beyond Imagination</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_10_knowledge-crystallization/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_10_knowledge-crystallization/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article introduces the concept of &quot;knowledge crystallization,&quot;  a process of abstracting and organizing existing knowledge to reveal deeper connections and insights. Using the example of flight and wings, the author demonstrates how seemingly disparate pieces of information can be synthesized into a cohesive understanding, revealing the wing&apos;s central role in all forms of flight. This synthesis, the author argues, creates a &quot;knowledge crystal.&quot;  The article further proposes a layered model for knowledge management: a &quot;Knowledge Lake&quot; for raw, unorganized knowledge; a &quot;Knowledge Base&quot; for structured knowledge; a &quot;Knowledge Gembox&quot; for crystallized insights; and a &quot;Knowledge Toolbox&quot; for practical applications derived from these crystals. The author emphasizes the potential for democratizing knowledge discovery, as anyone can contribute to crystallization, even leveraging AI,  leading to breakthroughs and innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Learning Intelligence System: The ALIS Concept</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_09_alis-concept/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_09_alis-concept/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The ALIS (Artificial Learning Intelligence System) concept integrates innate learning (neural network-based supervised learning) with acquired learning.  ALIS&apos;s core is extracting, storing, and utilizing reusable knowledge during inference. It&apos;s a system technology, not a single element, incorporating five elements: intellectual processor, knowledge store, world, state memory, and framework. ALIS uses natural language text for acquired knowledge, frameworks, and state memory, leveraging LLMs.  It categorizes knowledge into network parameter, natural, and formal knowledge; and stateless/stateful states.  ALIS&apos;s design enables agile development through incremental improvements. A simple ALIS implementation uses a chat AI with a mechanism to extract knowledge from chat history, storing it in a knowledge lake and structuring it into a knowledge base for retrieval.  Pre- and post-check comments enhance knowledge selection and utilization. The system is designed for software development initially, but its open-source nature allows community contribution and scalability across diverse domains, potentially even contributing to embodied AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_08_natural-language-ml/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_08_natural-language-ml/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Natural language machine learning leverages pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) to enable learning from textual data, unlike traditional machine learning that relies on numerical data.  A basic model is presented using supervised learning for classification, where an LLM processes input sentences and a knowledge base stores the LLM&apos;s responses and correctness judgments.  While a naive implementation is unrealistic, a more realistic model involves human assignment of inquiries, with corrections added to the knowledge base. This approach avoids altering the LLM&apos;s parameters and uses natural language feedback. The key advantage is greatly improved learning efficiency: natural language learning requires significantly less training data, no iterative learning, and minimal pre-processing compared to numerical machine learning, due to the LLM&apos;s ability to abstract and reason with language.  Therefore, while slower than numerical computation, natural language machine learning offers efficiency gains that might surpass the limitations of scaling up LLMs through purely numerical methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Presentation Video Generation from Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_06_auto-presentation-video/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_06_auto-presentation-video/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article details the author&apos;s development of a system that automatically generates presentation videos from blog posts using generative AI.  The core challenge was generating presentation materials (text and figures) in a text-based format (SVG) to avoid limitations of image-generating AIs.  A key problem was text overflow, addressed through instructing the AI with rules, procedures, and cautionary notes, and later with a custom program for rigorous detection.  Rule violations regarding figure complexity were also checked by the AI.  The system then generates a narration script from the blog post and the presentation material, converts it to audio using text-to-speech AI, and combines the audio and images into a final MP4 video using ffmpeg. While similar features are emerging from companies like Google, the author considers the project a significant learning experience in leveraging generative AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention Mechanism as Micro Virtual Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_06_micro-vm-intelligence/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_08_06_micro-vm-intelligence/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The article explores the Attention Mechanism in Transformer-based generative AI, comparing it to the concept of &apos;virtual intelligence.&apos; The Attention Mechanism, described as the core of the Transformer&apos;s success, allows AI to focus on relevant words when processing text, improving comprehension and context understanding.  The author introduces &apos;virtual intelligence&apos; as a future capability where AI can internally manage knowledge for different tasks, analogous to a virtual machine running multiple operating systems.  The key connection is drawn between the Attention Mechanism, which filters relevant words, and virtual intelligence, which filters relevant knowledge. The author proposes &apos;Micro Virtual Intelligence&apos; as a name for the Attention Mechanism due to its parallel function at a word level. Conversely, a &apos;Macro Attention Mechanism&apos;, or &apos;Explicit Attention Mechanism&apos;, could be implemented through explicit instructions (e.g., &apos;for task X, use knowledge Y and Z&apos;), making it easier to manage knowledge for complex tasks. This explicit approach also allows for iterative refinement of knowledge based on task success or failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions of Spatial Perception: The Potential of AI</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_space-dimension-ai/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_space-dimension-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article explores the potential of AI to perceive and utilize higher-dimensional spaces, exceeding human capabilities.  Humans perceive 3D space by interpreting 2D visual data; the author proposes that AI could similarly process and understand 4D (and higher) spaces by directly processing multi-dimensional data. This would enable AI to analyze multi-dimensional graphs panoramically, revealing patterns and relationships invisible to humans or conventional AI. The author argues this capability could revolutionize scientific discovery, accelerating paradigm shifts in various fields by providing a native understanding of high-dimensional data, potentially leading to breakthroughs similar to the shift from geocentrism to heliocentrism. While humans may struggle to comprehend these high-dimensional paradigms, the benefits of the resulting technologies might outweigh the limitations of our understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Symphonic Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_symphonic-intelligence/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_symphonic-intelligence/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article explores the future of generative AI in business, focusing on the shift from using AI as a tool for iterative tasks to incorporating it into systems for flow-based work.  Iterative work, while benefiting from AI tools, remains limited by human capacity and skill gaps.  The author proposes converting iterative work into standardized flow work, allowing better AI integration and knowledge sharing. This systematization leads to improved efficiency and scalability, allowing the AI to progressively take on more tasks.  The article then introduces the concept of &quot;virtual intelligence,&quot; where a single AI switches roles and knowledge to handle tasks efficiently, like a virtual machine.  This capability, combined with &quot;intelligence orchestration,&quot; leads to &quot;Symphonic Intelligence,&quot; where multiple AI roles work together seamlessly, mimicking human intellectual flexibility.  The ultimate goal is an AGI capable of learning new tasks quickly through observation, exceeding human learning capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration of Virtual Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_virtual-intelligence-orchestration/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_30_virtual-intelligence-orchestration/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article introduces &quot;intelligence orchestration,&quot; a method of using a single AI to perform complex tasks by switching between multiple virtual intelligences with different roles, similar to system orchestration using virtual machines.  Unlike system orchestration, which requires system development to combine multiple AIs, intelligence orchestration uses prompt instructions within a single AI. This allows for more flexible and rapid development.  The article highlights &quot;ultimate deliberation,&quot; a process where the AI iteratively refines its approach to problem-solving by combining multiple perspectives, leading to more precise and creative thought.  This approach enables AI to learn from failures and improve its knowledge base, significantly increasing the potential for AI to replace human tasks in business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation Thinking and the Origin of Life</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_29_simulation-thinking/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_29_simulation-thinking/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article introduces &quot;simulation thinking,&quot; a method of tracing accumulation and interaction to understand complex phenomena.  The author applies this to the origin of life, arguing against explanations relying on chance and instead proposing a gradual, planet-wide process.  Simple chemicals, through repeated reactions and global circulation, formed increasingly complex substances, exhibiting self-maintenance and replication-like properties.  This initial step, the author contends, is the essence of life&apos;s origin. The process is facilitated by polymers, Earth&apos;s topography (providing isolated environments), and a &apos;cloud of dust&apos; shielding the planet from UV radiation and acting as a monomer factory.  The article concludes by emphasizing simulation thinking&apos;s importance, particularly in software development, where translating natural language requirements into functional programs necessitates this dual-faceted approach to simulating both the program&apos;s internal workings and the user&apos;s needs.  The author proposes &quot;Natural Mathematics,&quot; a natural language approach to mathematical expression, to facilitate simulation thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow Work Conversion and Systems: The Essence of Generative AI Utilization</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_29_tool-vs-system/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_29_tool-vs-system/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article emphasizes the crucial role of &quot;flow work conversion&quot; and systematization in maximizing the productivity and quality improvements offered by generative AI.  It distinguishes between &quot;iteration work&quot; (flexible, trial-and-error) and &quot;flow work&quot; (incremental, with a final deliverable).  The author argues that simply using AI as a tool for iteration work yields limited results. Instead, converting human tasks into clearly defined flow work processes, and subsequently systematizing those flows with AI, unlocks the true potential of generative AI.  This approach mirrors historical technological shifts like the Industrial and IT revolutions. The article uses the example of handling employee inquiries to illustrate how flow work conversion and systematization, with AI handling individual tasks within the flow, drastically increases efficiency compared to using AI merely as a tool for iterative tasks.  The author addresses common misconceptions about generative AI&apos;s limitations, highlighting that the key lies not in AI&apos;s direct replacement of iterative tasks, but in its integration into well-defined, automated workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnidirectional Engineers in the Liquidware Era</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_28_liquidware-allrounder/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_28_liquidware-allrounder/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Generative AI significantly impacts software development, enabling automated programming and ushering in the &quot;Liquidware&quot; era. Liquidware refers to software highly customizable by users via generative AI, allowing personalized modifications to functions and interfaces. This necessitates a shift towards &quot;omnidirectional engineers,&quot; professionals possessing broad expertise across various system stacks, rather than specializing in a single area like programming.  These engineers oversee system design, interoperability of complex systems, and risk mitigation, leveraging generative AI for programming tasks.  The article illustrates this with an example of an ambitious e-commerce platform integration project, highlighting the role of omnidirectional engineers in managing such complex, multifaceted development initiatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fate of Thinking: AI and Humanity</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_12_fate-of-thinking/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_12_fate-of-thinking/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article explores the shift in thinking required of humans in an AI-driven world.  The author argues that while AI will handle intellectual labor, a new form of thinking, focusing on &apos;individual optimization,&apos; will be crucial.  This contrasts with past &apos;overall optimization&apos; approaches.  The author introduces &apos;process-oriented software&apos; as a new paradigm emphasizing individual processes, mirroring the societal shift towards &apos;individual optimization society&apos;.  This necessitates &apos;subjective philosophy,&apos; where deep deliberation and individual framework design for each situation become paramount. The author concludes that AI frees humans from rote intellectual labor, but simultaneously demands deeper, more responsible thinking, making &apos;the fate of thinking&apos; a continuous, even more vital human endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invitation to Business Process-Oriented Software</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_11_business-process-oriented/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_07_11_business-process-oriented/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article introduces business process-oriented software, a new approach to software development that integrates business manuals and input information into a single executable file.  Unlike traditional object-oriented software, this approach focuses on the business process as the fundamental unit, making modifications and additions easier.  The file, which can be a simple text file like Markdown, serves as the software, executed by humans or AI.  AI can assist by automating tasks, prompting human input through user-friendly interfaces, and accumulating knowledge for continuous improvement. This system aims to create a &quot;fast learning organization&quot; where humans focus on minimal, high-level tasks while AI handles complex processes and adaptation, leading to increased efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework Design as an Intellectual Ability</title>
      <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_06_29_framework-design-ability/</link>
      <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/en/articles/2025_06_29_framework-design-ability/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>This article contrasts the intellectual activities of academic discovery (observation-based fact-finding) and development (design-based invention). While academia typically focuses on discovery, the author argues that &apos;framework design&apos; represents a crucial inventive aspect within academia, exemplified by scientific paradigm shifts like the geocentric/heliocentric models and the evolution of physics theories.  These shifts are presented not as complete replacements but as additions of useful frameworks.  The article highlights the differing skill sets required for discovery and design, suggesting that while many academics excel at discovery within existing frameworks, the skill of framework design is less common, despite its importance.  While engineers generally possess design skills, these are often field-specific.  The author posits that software engineers, due to their experience in designing abstract concepts, are uniquely positioned to contribute to academic framework design, provided they possess advanced abstract design skills and a habit of contemplating new design models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>