<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Articles (pcm)</title>
<link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/rss.xml</link>
<description>Latest articles (pcm)</description>
<item>
  <title>Entering an Era Wey No Get Borders: How I Make 30-Language Blog Site</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_24_Wall-Free-Era/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_24_Wall-Free-Era/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The author details how they built an automated, multilingual blog website using generative AI, specifically Gemini. The system, built on the Astro framework, automatically generates HTML files from Japanese blog post drafts. Gemini was used to develop the core program, categorize and tag articles, and translate content into 30 languages. The author highlights Gemini's role in improving accessibility features and handling language-specific nuances like date formats and right-to-left writing systems. The process involves automatically updating the site, categorizing content, and translating common phrases and article drafts. This approach significantly overcomes barriers of language, translation quality, accessibility, and site maintenance, making information dissemination more accessible to individuals.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Kunu Developmen We De Kun De Develop, With Refactoring-Driven Testing</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_19_Dev-Development/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_19_Dev-Development/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article discusses a new approach to software development called "Kunu Development" which leverages generative AI to create developer tools concurrently with the main software development process. This iterative creation of helper software aims to improve efficiency and quality over time. The article also introduces "Refactoring-Driven Testing," an alternative to Test-Driven Development (TDD), suggesting that testing becomes more crucial during refactoring phases rather than at the initial design stage, especially for software with subjective user experience elements. This approach prioritizes testing mature features while leaving fluid components without automated tests. Both "Kunu Development" and "Refactoring-Driven Testing" are presented as advancements pushing software development towards more advanced, experience-centric, and omni-directional engineering.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Time Wey Dey Rush Us &amp; Things Wey We No Know: Why We Need Rules</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_16_Time-Compression-Blindspot/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_16_Time-Compression-Blindspot/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article discusses the rapid advancement of AI, particularly generative AI, and its implications for society. It highlights that while technological progress is generally beneficial, excessively fast advancement can lead to risks outweighing benefits due to societal blind spots. Developers may not fully understand new technologies, and society's ability to adapt and integrate these changes is outpaced. This creates a situation where unforeseen risks can emerge, leading to significant harm. The author introduces the concept of "Chronos-Scramble Society" to describe a state where individual perceptions of time and technological progress differ significantly, making common understanding and planning difficult. To address this, the article proposes establishing stable, long-term visions and strategies that acknowledge these differing perceptions. It suggests using AI itself as a tool to manage and stabilize technological development, acting as a "built-in stabilizer" to mitigate risks and ensure benefits.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GitHub as "Afa Intellectual"</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_15_Intellectual-Mine-GitHub/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores GitHub's potential beyond software development, positioning it as a central "intellectual mine" for "intellectual factories." These factories, powered by generative AI, can automate content creation and transformation across various media. The author introduces "DeepWiki," an AI that generates wiki sites for GitHub projects, and their personal concept of an "intellectual factory" for automating blog content creation and dissemination. Both DeepWiki and the author's factory are seen as examples of generative AI transforming raw materials (code or text) into structured knowledge bases. The article predicts GitHub will become a massive, shared public knowledge base, facilitating AI pre-training and knowledge discovery through processes akin to RAG. This system will foster the growth of "knowledge crystals" or "catalytic knowledge" – ideas and frameworks that accelerate further knowledge creation and discovery, distinct from traditional scientific knowledge.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>If Sense Dey Marry Logic, E Go Born Sabi-Sabi</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_14_Intuition-and-Logic/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the connection between intuition and logic, arguing that they are not opposing forces but can be synthesized through a process called 'intellectual crystallization'. The author contends that many intuitive beliefs, when faced with logical scrutiny, are abandoned or dismissed as mere opinions. This is often because the underlying assumptions or aims differ.  The article uses 'national interest' versus 'world peace' as a case study, demonstrating how the former, though often presented as a logical imperative for national survival and prosperity, is ultimately unpredictable and potentially detrimental in the long term.  Instead, the author proposes focusing on accumulating factors like lasting peace, good governance, economic prosperity, and risk management.  This synthesis of intuition and logic, termed 'natural mathematics', aims to bridge the gap between what feels right and what can be logically explained, leading to more robust and well-founded reasoning.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ideational Gestalt Collapse</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_14_Concept-Gestalt-Collapse/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces "Ideational Gestalt Collapse," a phenomenon where the more an idea is analyzed, the more its initial simple truth seems to disintegrate. The author uses the example of a "chair" to illustrate this, showing how attempts to define it by material, shape, or function can lead to its conceptual breakdown.  To maintain "Ideational Gestalt," the author proposes focusing on functionality, relativity, and holism. The article then applies this concept to consciousness in fictional characters and future robots, suggesting that our perception of their sentience is influenced by immersion and context.  Finally, it argues that common arguments against current AI consciousness often represent Ideational Gestalt Collapse, proposing that a functional, relative, and holistic view is essential for understanding AI sentience, much like understanding what constitutes a "chair."</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How Dem Dey Learn How To Learn: Born With Sense</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_13_Natural-Born-Frameworker/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the concept of "learning to learn" in artificial intelligence, particularly in large language models (LLMs). It distinguishes between "sub-physical learning" (rote memorization) and "metaphysical learning" (understanding and applying knowledge with minimal repetition). Natural language is presented as a key "metaphysical connection point" that facilitates metaphysical learning. The article introduces "frameworks" as structures that define relationships between concepts, evolving from "virtual frameworks" (expressed in language) to "native frameworks" (directly understood and used). LLMs, through mechanisms like attention, are theorized to be "natural born frameworkers," learning frameworks incrementally from simple to complex. This process explains how LLMs achieve sophisticated understanding and adaptation. The author suggests that this "natural born frameworker" capability, enabled by natural language's inherent structure, mirrors human learning processes, hinting that humans are also natural born frameworkers. The article posits that natural languages themselves evolve based on their effectiveness in facilitating this learning process.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chronoscramble Society</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_12_Chronoscramble-Society/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the concept of a "Chronoscramble Society," a society where generative AI causes significant differences in how people perceive time. Unlike previous time perception gaps, which were often tied to socioeconomic factors, culture, or generations, the AI-driven gaps are more complex and wider, even among experts. These differences manifest in understanding current AI capabilities, the application of technologies, and future predictions, leading to communication challenges and difficulties in decision-making. The author argues that these gaps are persistent and require new approaches to communication and decision-making that acknowledge and work around these differing perceptions, rather than trying to eliminate them entirely. The article draws parallels to the game "Chrono Trigger" as an example of successful collaboration despite differing perspectives.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Di Taim We Go De Tink Like Say Na Simulation</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_12_Simulation-Thinking-Era/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores how generative AI is transforming software development and simulation systems. It introduces "intellectual factories" that use generative AI to automate content creation and "omnidirectional engineering" for complete system development. The author highlights "liquidware" for its flexibility and adaptability, contrasting it with traditional rigid software.  The piece also discusses a shift towards "business process-oriented development" over monolithic structures, arguing that generative AI makes individualized process improvements more advantageous.  In simulation systems, generative AI facilitates the creation of complex models, including those involving qualitative data and human-like agents, and allows natural language input. This enables more accurate, efficient simulations and transforms discussions from subjective arguments to collaborative model refinement, fostering "simulation thinking" over intuition-based approaches.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knowledge Wey Don Pure Pass Imagination: Wings Wey Carry Us Go Far</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_10_Knowledge-Crystallization/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces the concept of "crystallized knowledge," defined as comprehensive and consistent knowledge that integrates information from various angles, including laws. Using the example of how airplanes fly, the author explains how wings contribute to lift, thrust, and airflow manipulation, demonstrating how complex flight can be understood through the principles of wing design. The author then proposes a framework for knowledge processing: starting with a "knowledge lake" (raw, unorganized knowledge), moving to a "knowledge base" (organized knowledge), then to a "knowledge gem box" (pure, refined knowledge), and finally to a "knowledge toolbox" (practical application of knowledge). The core idea is that even existing, widely known information can be refined through careful arrangement and combination to create new insights and practical tools, a process accessible to everyone, including artificial intelligence.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wetin Be Experience &amp; Behavior?</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_10_Experience-Behavior/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces 'Experience &amp; Behavior Engineering' as a new paradigm for software development, contrasting it with traditional 'specifications-and-implementation-based engineering'. The author argues that user experience, shaped by software behavior, is becoming paramount. Traditional methods, focused on fixed plans and implementations, are insufficient for this new approach, especially with the advent of AI-driven development and 'liquidware'. Liquidware describes software that is highly adaptable and customizable to individual user preferences, akin to how humans control their own bodies. Behavior testing, therefore, shifts from verifying adherence to specifications to evaluating the quality of user experience, including the absence of bugs and the effectiveness of functions. The ultimate goal is to create liquidware that offers a seamless, intuitive experience, making complex or limited systems feel effortless to control, much like our own healthy bodies.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Artificial Learning Intelligence System: ALIS Wey Dem Call Am</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_09_ALIS-Concept/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces the Artificial Learning Intelligence System (ALIS), designed to integrate "innate learning" (like neural networks) with "acquired learning" (knowledge stored externally). ALIS focuses on effectively extracting, storing, and utilizing knowledge. It comprises five key components: Intelligent Processor (e.g., LLMs, brain), Knowledge Store (parameters, memory), World (environment), State Memory (scratchpad), and Framework (rules for reasoning). ALIS principles involve continuous learning cycles where the processor acts on the world, extracts knowledge, and refines its actions. Acquired knowledge is primarily targeted as natural language text for easier processing, sharing, and verification. The system can also utilize formal languages and models for stricter reasoning. ALIS can manage knowledge across network parameters, natural language, and formal languages, distinguishing between stateless and stateful types. "Intellectual Orchestration" is proposed to manage specialized knowledge stores for complex tasks. Development follows an agile approach, starting with a simple chat AI integrated with a knowledge lake and base, then enhancing it with pre-analysis and post-checking using state memory. This approach allows for iterative improvement and can be applied to various intellectual activities, potentially leading to virtually embodied or physically embodied AI.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Machine Learning Wey Dem Dey Use Natural Language Do</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_08_Natural-Language-ML/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces Natural Language Machine Learning (NLML), a new approach that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to learn from text data instead of traditional numerical data. Unlike conventional machine learning, where parameters are updated, NLML uses pre-trained LLMs and stores learning outcomes in a knowledge base using natural language. A basic model is described, akin to supervised classification, where an LLM generates answers to prompts, and a teacher system evaluates them, storing correct input-answer pairs and judgments in a knowledge base. This knowledge base then augments subsequent prompts. The article highlights NLML's efficiency, requiring less data, no retraining, and minimal preprocessing compared to numerical machine learning. It posits that as LLMs approach scaling limits, NLML will become a primary focus for improving AI capabilities.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Way "Attention Mechanism" Dey Work Small Small Like Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/08_06_Micro-VM-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the "attention mechanism," a key innovation behind the success of Transformer-based generative AI. It explains how this mechanism allows AI to focus on relevant words in a sentence, improving comprehension, especially for long or complex texts. The author draws parallels between the attention mechanism and a concept called "virtual intelligence," defining virtual intelligence as an AI's ability to internally switch between relevant knowledge based on the task at hand, similar to how a virtual machine runs different operating systems. The article suggests that the attention mechanism can be seen as a "micro virtual intelligence" because it narrows down focus to relevant words. It further proposes an "explicit attention mechanism" or "attention knowledge" in the form of clear natural language instructions, which can guide AI without altering its core structure and can be updated based on performance. Ultimately, the article posits that the attention mechanism is fundamental to advancing intelligence layer by layer, influencing both how AI processes information and the development of more sophisticated AI capabilities.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How We dey Arrange Virtual Intelligence</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Virtual-Intelligence-Orchestration/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces the concept of "virtual intelligence" (VI) as the ability for artificial intelligence to simulate human-like reasoning and role-playing, similar to how virtual machines simulate computer hardware. It explains that VI is already present in conversational AI. The core idea is "intelligence orchestration," which contrasts with "system orchestration." While system orchestration combines different AI systems, intelligence orchestration uses a single AI model that internally orchestrates multiple "virtual intelligences" through prompt instructions. This approach allows for "ultimate deliberation," enabling AIs to iteratively refine their thinking, combine diverse perspectives, and learn from mistakes without requiring extensive system development. The article concludes that VI, through intelligence orchestration and ultimate deliberation, can significantly enhance AI capabilities, allowing them to perform complex intellectual tasks and potentially replace humans in more roles.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Di Taim We Symphonic Intelligence Take Over</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Symphonic-Intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the evolution of generative AI from a simple tool to a core component of business operations, introducing the concept of "Symphonic Intelligence." It contrasts "iterative work," which relies on human expertise and tools, with "flow work," where tasks are systematized and can be performed by AI or humans within a system. The author argues that traditional iterative work faces limitations due to human capacity and skill gaps. To overcome this, work needs to transition to a flow-based system, allowing generative AI to specialize in tasks and enabling human knowledge integration. The article also introduces "virtual intelligence," where AI can switch between roles and knowledge within a single process, similar to virtual machines, and "intelligence orchestration" for managing these AI roles. Symphonic Intelligence is presented as the ultimate stage, where AI can perform complex intellectual tasks flexibly and adaptively, mirroring human capabilities. This level of AI could lead to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), capable of learning and sharing knowledge across tasks, ultimately automating complex intellectual labor.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How We See Space: AI Fit Come Help</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_30_Space-Dimension-AI/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores how Artificial Intelligence (AI) can overcome human limitations in perceiving and understanding multi-dimensional spaces. While humans visualize 3D space from 2D retinal input, AI can be trained to directly process and understand higher-dimensional data, such as 4D graphs, without information loss or the need for projection. This ability allows AI to identify trends, patterns, and relationships across numerous dimensions that are imperceptible to humans. By directly analyzing multi-dimensional data in its original form, AI can significantly accelerate scientific discovery, potentially leading to breakthroughs akin to the heliocentric theory or the theories of relativity and quantum mechanics, but much faster. The article suggests that AI's advanced dimensional perception could lead to new scientific laws and paradigms. However, it also notes that humans might eventually rely on complex systems they don't fully comprehend, a situation not entirely dissimilar to current human reliance on technology.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flow-Based Work and Systems: Wetin Be True-True Use Of Generative AI</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_29_Tool-vs-System/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explains that the true value of generative AI in business comes from transforming iterative work into flow-based processes and then systematizing them, rather than just using AI as a tool for existing iterative tasks. The author draws parallels with the Industrial and IT Revolutions, where systematizing work led to significant efficiency gains. While generative AI can adapt quickly to tasks, its potential is maximized when integrated into structured, step-by-step flows. The article critiques the common misunderstanding of using generative AI for isolated, iterative tasks, which yields limited improvements. It emphasizes that changing human-centric iterative work into flow-based processes is challenging due to human adaptability limitations, but generative AI, with its ability to learn and adapt to new instructions quickly, is well-suited for this transformation. The key is to define work processes in detail, integrate AI into these flows, and continuously refine the AI's instructions based on performance, ultimately creating self-improving systems.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wetin Be "Simulation Thinking" Na Him Make Life Start</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_29_Simulation-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article introduces "simulation thinking" as a method to understand complex processes by tracing how small elements accumulate and interact step-by-step to produce a final outcome. This approach is applied to the origin of life, suggesting it wasn't a sudden miracle but a gradual process of chemical self-organization driven by Earth's environment. The author posits that early Earth had conditions favoring the formation of complex chemical substances through atmospheric circulation, dust clouds acting as monomer factories, and numerous interconnected water bodies serving as experimental sites. This initial step, marked by the existence of simple complex chemicals, laid the groundwork for further evolution towards more complex life forms. The article also highlights simulation thinking's relevance in software development, where developers use it to translate user needs and system interactions into functional programs, differentiating between "principled simulation thinking" (understanding system mechanics) and "semantic simulation thinking" (understanding user goals). The author concludes that simulation thinking, particularly when combined with "natural mathematics," is a crucial skill for tackling complex scientific and societal challenges.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Di Omnidirectional Engineer For Di Liquidware Era</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_28_Liquidware-Allrounder/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the evolving landscape of software development driven by generative AI, introducing the concepts of "liquidware" and the "omnidirectional engineer." Liquidware refers to software that users can easily customize through AI, allowing for personalized user experiences. Generative AI's ability to automate programming tasks is reducing the reliance on traditional coding skills, leading to a shift in demand from specialized full-stack engineers to "omnidirectional engineers." These engineers possess broad knowledge across multiple system stacks and can design and manage complex, integrated software systems. The article posits that this evolution will enable more agile development, user-driven customization, and ultimately, the creation of highly adaptable software solutions, impacting how businesses and society function.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wetin We Go Dey Think: AI At Plenti Bobo</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_12_Fate-of-Thinking/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article explores the future of human thinking and society in an age of advanced AI, proposing a shift from "object-orientation" to "process-orientation" in software development and from "global optimization" to "individual optimization" in societal organization. The author argues that as AI takes over routine "sense work," humans will need to engage in "different kinds of thinking," focusing on nuanced, individual problem-solving. In software, "process-orientation" emphasizes understanding the entire flow of operations as a single unit, allowing for easier modularity and adaptation. In society, "individually optimized" systems will prioritize unique circumstances over universal rules, mirroring concepts like "extenuating circumstances" in law. This leads to the idea of "subjective philosophy," where deep, personal thinking about each situation has intrinsic value. The author concludes that AI will free humans from tasks but not from the fundamental need to think, making deep, individualistic thought and judgment essential for our future.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to do Business Better (Business Process Orientation)</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/07_11_Business-Process-Oriented/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>This article introduces Business Process-Oriented Software as a novel approach to software development, contrasting it with traditional object-oriented software. It posits that aligning software design with natural human understanding of processes can lead to significant gains in maintainability and adaptability. The core concept is to encapsulate business processes, including manuals, data input, and contact information, into single, unified files. These files act as the software itself, executable by humans or AI. Unlike conventional systems that separate manuals from processing, this approach integrates them, simplifying updates and reducing development/maintenance costs. The article further explores how AI can actively assist in executing these processes, either directly or by facilitating human interaction through user-friendly interfaces. It highlights Markdown as a suitable format for AI compatibility. By centralizing process knowledge and enabling continuous improvement through AI-assisted file manipulation, organizations can achieve rapid learning and enhanced efficiency, allowing humans to focus on essential tasks while AI handles complex information and process adaptations.</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to Design Frameworks as Something Wey Your Brain Dey Do</title>
  <link>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</link>
  <guid>https://katoshi-mfacet.github.io/pcm/articles/2025/06_29_Framework-Design-Ability/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <description>The article differentiates between "finding facts by observation" typical of academic research and "inventing things and systems through design" crucial for development. While basic sciences focus on discovery, engineering disciplines are seen as "practical sciences" that integrate knowledge from development. The author argues that framework design, exemplified by scientific models like geocentric/heliocentric and Newtonian mechanics, is a form of invention through design, not discovery. These frameworks are valued for their usefulness in specific contexts rather than absolute correctness. The author proposes "paradigm inventions" or "paradigm innovations" as more accurate terms than "paradigm shifts." The article highlights that while academic researchers often specialize in observation-based discovery within existing frameworks, the skill set for invention through design is distinct and often underdeveloped in academia. Conversely, software engineers are particularly well-suited for framework design because their work inherently involves rearranging abstract concepts at a meta-level, a skill transferable to academic framework design with advanced abstract concept design abilities and a habit of thinking about new design models.</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>